- Are you ready, kids?
- 孩子们，你们准备好了吗？
all: Aye aye, captain!
全体：是啊，队长！
- I can't hear you.
- 我听不到你说话。
all: Aye aye, captain!
全体：是啊，队长！
- Oh...
[water bubbles]
- 哦...
[水泡]
♪ Who lives in a pineapple
under the sea? ♪
♪ 谁住在菠萝里
在海底？ ♪
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
- ♪ Absorbent and yellow
and porous is he ♪
- ♪ 吸水性和黄色
他是多孔的 ♪
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
- ♪ If nautical nonsense
be something you wish ♪
- ♪ 如果航海废话
成为你想要的东西♪
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
- ♪ Then drop on the deck
and flop like a fish ♪
- ♪ 然后落在甲板上
然后像鱼一样扑通扑通♪
all: SpongeBob SquarePants!
- Ready?
所有：海绵宝宝！
- 准备好？
all: SpongeBob SquarePants!
所有：海绵宝宝！
SpongeBob SquarePants!
海绵宝宝！
- ♪ SpongeBob ♪
- ♪ 海绵宝宝 ♪
♪ SquarePants! ♪
♪ 方裤！ ♪
[laughing]
[笑]
♪ ♪
[waves crashing]
[海浪拍打]
[slack-key guitar music]
[松键吉他音乐]
♪ ♪
- Mm, mm.
- 嗯，嗯。
[raspberry blows]
Oh.
[覆盆子吹]
哦。
- [whimpers]
- [blowing raspberries]
- [呜咽]
- [吹覆盆子]
all: [gasp]
全体：[喘气]
- Mustard, mustard, step right
up for your mustard.
- 芥末，芥末，向右走
准备你的芥末。
Some mustard for you.
[bottle blows raspberries]
给你一些芥末。
[瓶子吹覆盆子]
Eh, eh, eh.
呃，呃，呃。
- [growls]
- [咆哮]
- Cool!
- 凉爽的！
- A bit of the yellow for you.
- 给你一点黄色。
Doy.
多伊。
[ship whistles and glops]
[船的汽笛声和咕噜声]
- [giggles]
- [咯咯笑]
- [indistinct whispering]
- Oh, okay.
- [含糊不清的窃窃私语]
- 哦，好吧。
Eh.
呃。
[accordion music]
[手风琴音乐]
And a Mr. Mustard for you.
还有芥末先生送给你。
- [purrs]
Mmm, yummy.
- [呼噜声]
嗯，好吃。
- Hyah!
- 哈！
- [coughs]
[droplet plinks]
- [咳嗽]
[水滴叮当响]
all: Aw.
全体：噢。
- Hang on, folks, I'll be right
back with more mustard.
- 等一下，伙计们，我马上就来
回来加更多芥末。
[engine turns over]
[发动机转动]
Whoo!
[tires squeal]
呼！
[轮胎吱吱声]
Let's see.
让我们来看看。
Ketchup.
番茄酱。
Mayonnaise.
蛋黄酱。
Oh, mustard.
哦，芥末。
- Did you use up
all me mustard?
- 你用完了吗
我都是芥末吗？
- [stammering]
What?
- [结巴]
什么？
- Oh, who gives
a flying fish about mustard?
- 哦，谁给的
一条关于芥末的飞鱼？
- [gasps]
- [喘气]
But Squidward, without mustard
I wouldn't be able to make a--
但是章鱼哥，没有芥末
我无法做出——
- Krabby Patty.
- 克拉比帕蒂。
That's right, you're both
hereby ordered
没错，你们俩都是
特此命令
to go down into
the mustard mines.
深入到
芥末矿。
And bring me back more mustard.
给我带回来更多的芥末。
- Mustard mines?
- 芥末地雷？
- Mmm, mustard.
- 嗯，芥末。
Uh...
呃...
Ah.
啊。
[burps]
[打嗝]
- [grunts]
- [咕哝]
And you are going down
to the mustard mines too.
而你正在下降
也到芥末矿。
- I wouldn't do that
if I was you.
- 我不会那样做
如果我是你。
[ominous music]
[不祥的音乐]
[spits]
[sizzling]
[吐口水]
[嘶嘶声]
That old mustard mine
is cursed.
那个老芥末矿
被诅咒了。
- Cursed?
- What kind of curse?
- 被诅咒了？
- 什么样的诅咒？
- It's, uh, er, one of those--
- 这是，呃，呃，其中之一--
The Mummy's Curse.
木乃伊的诅咒。
- [snickers] There's no
such thing as mummies.
- [窃笑]没有
诸如木乃伊之类的东西。
- We've all got mummies.
- 我们都有木乃伊。
Eh?
[giggles]
呃？
[咯咯笑]
Mm-hmm.
嗯嗯。
I've been in that mine.
我一直在那个矿井里。
No one that enters
gets out alive.
没有人进入
活着出去。
- [shrieking]
[spooky music]
- [尖叫]
[诡异的音乐]
[thunder roars]
[雷霆怒吼]
- You got out and you're alive.
- 你出去了，你还活着。
- Ah, but am I?
- 啊，但是我是吗？
- Yeah, you're standing
right there.
- 是的，你站着
就在那里。
- But am I?
- 但我是吗？
- Yeah, you're right--
- 是的，你说得对--
Hmm.
唔。
- I see your foot.
- 我看到你的脚了。
- No, you don't.
- 不，你不知道。
- Ah, his foot's gone!
- 啊，他的脚没了！
[seagull caws]
[海鸥的叫声]
- This map doesn't show us
- 这张地图没有向我们展示
where the mustard vein
is located.
芥末脉在哪里
位于。
Well, let's just start picking.
好吧，让我们开始挑选吧。
- Way ahead of you, pal.
- 远远领先于你，朋友。
- Ugh.
- 呃。
- [nose pops]
- [鼻子爆裂]
Ooh.
哦。
[brain smearing]
[脑涂片]
- [grunts]
- [咕哝]
both: [gasp]
Oh.
两人：[喘气]
哦。
♪ A-mining we will go ♪
♪ 我们要去 A 采矿 ♪
♪ The mustard, it will flow ♪
♪ 芥末，它会流动 ♪
♪ With pick and axe
Without the facts ♪
♪ 用镐和斧头
没有事实依据♪
♪ There's nothing
that we know ♪
♪ 什么都没有
我们都知道♪
Ta-da.
[mine rumbles]
哒哒。
[地雷的隆隆声]
- Huh?
- 啊？
You nitwits.
你们这些白痴。
How will we get out now?
现在我们怎么出去？
- Ah, we're trapped in a mine.
- 啊，我们被困在矿井里了。
We'll never get out.
我们永远出不去。
[grunting]
[咕噜声]
[whimpering]
[呜咽]
[groans]
[呻吟]
- [sighs]
- [叹气]
- Krabby Patty, stat.
- 克拉比·帕蒂，统计数据。
- Mm.
- 毫米。
[dramatic music]
[戏剧音乐]
[playful music]
[俏皮的音乐]
- [chomping]
- [咀嚼]
Oh.
[gulps]
哦。
[吞咽]
- He's coming 'round.
- Squidward.
- 他回来了。
- 章鱼哥。
I--I need--
- What can I get for you?
我——我需要——
- 我能为你买点什么？
- I need a little mustard
for the Krabby Patty.
- 我需要一点芥末
蟹肉饼。
- Why do I even bother?
- 为什么我还要麻烦呢？
Maybe there's a back door.
也许有后门。
both: Hey, wait for us.
两人：嘿，等我们一下。
- Whoa.
- 哇哦。
- I wonder how deep it is.
- 我想知道它有多深。
- I'll check.
- 我会检查一下。
Wahhh!
哇哦！
Don't bother jumping.
That shaft has no bottom.
别费心跳了。
那个轴没有底部。
Let's take the escalator.
我们乘自动扶梯吧。
- All right, spread out.
- 好吧，散开。
[calm elevator music]
[平静的电梯音乐]
- Coal miners.
- 煤矿工人。
Ew.
呃。
- Sulfur miners.
- 硫磺矿工。
- Phew.
- 唷。
Unaccompanied minors.
[drum sting]
无人陪伴的未成年人。
[鼓刺]
♪ ♪
- All right, let's get to work,
chowderheads.
- 好吧，我们开始工作吧
海鲜杂烩浓汤。
- [grunts]
- [咕哝]
Hey, I found something yellow.
嘿，我发现了一些黄色的东西。
[groans]
[呻吟]
Never mind, it's just gold.
没关系，这只是金子。
- All I'm getting
is dumb old diamonds.
- 我所得到的一切
是愚蠢的老钻石。
- This must be
the Mummy's Curse
- 这一定是
木乃伊的诅咒
that old guy
was talking about.
那个老家伙
正在谈论。
- Gold and diamonds?
- 黄金和钻石？
[grunting]
[咕噜声]
Gold dust.
金粉。
No, no, it's just sand.
不不不，这只是沙子。
- [blowing raspberries]
Whoa!
- [吹覆盆子]
哇！
[screaming]
[尖叫]
- Ah.
- 啊。
- [screaming]
- [尖叫]
- Uh, what was that?
- 呃，那是什么？
- Ah, the greatest
treasure of all,
- 啊，最伟大的
一切的宝藏，
a child.
一个孩子。
[sniffing]
[嗅嗅]
[playful music]
[俏皮的音乐]
[grunts]
[咕哝]
[telephone rings]
[电话铃声]
Hello?
你好？
- SpongeBob,
where's me mustard?
- 海绵宝宝，
我芥末在哪里？
[angry chatter]
- I want some mus--
[愤怒的喋喋不休]
-我想要一些音乐--
- On the way, sir,
as soon as we find it.
- 先生，在路上，
一旦我们找到它。
Love you.
爱你。
- Oh, we'll never find
that mustard vein.
-哦，我们永远找不到
那芥末静脉。
Oh.
哦。
What is this?
这是什么？
- Local train
approaching station.
- 当地火车
接近车站。
[train rumbles]
[火车隆隆声]
[ominous music]
[不祥的音乐]
[slack-key guitar music]
[松键吉他音乐]
- Hurry up, Squidward,
before the doors close.
- 快点，章鱼哥
在门关闭之前。
- It's the last train
of the night.
- 这是末班车
当晚的。
- Do you have a metro card?
- 你有地铁卡吗？
- [frantically grunting]
- [疯狂地咕哝]
Ah, I got it.
啊，我明白了。
[grunting]
[咕噜声]
- Come on, Squidward!
- 来吧，章鱼哥！
- Watch the closing doors.
- 注意关闭的门。
- [grunting]
[card reader beeps]
- [咕哝]
[读卡器发出蜂鸣声]
- Faster, Squidward, faster!
- [groaning]
- 快点，章鱼哥，快点！
- [呻吟]
♪ ♪
- Hey, Squidward, you really
should watch the closing doors.
- 嘿，章鱼哥，你真的
应该留意关闭的门。
- [growls]
- [咆哮]
- This is a local mining train
- 这是当地的采矿列车
making all stops between
Coal and Limestone.
之间的所有停留
煤和石灰石。
Next stop, Condiments.
下一站，调味品。
- Oh, that's our stop.
- 哦，那是我们的站。
♪ ♪
- [groans]
- [呻吟]
[thumps]
[重击]
- Come on, Squidward.
- 来吧，章鱼哥。
- [head bangs]
- [刘海]
[grunts]
[咕哝]
♪ ♪
Hmm.
唔。
Ah, la, hmm.
Ah.
啊，啦，嗯。
啊。
I've struck mayo.
我已经打了蛋黄酱。
- [grunts]
- [咕哝]
Hot sauce.
辣酱。
- Ah.
- 啊。
I struck blood.
我撞到了血。
Oh, no, it's ketchup.
哦，不，这是番茄酱。
[slurps]
[啜饮]
- We're getting close.
- 我们已经很接近了。
[harp music]
[竖琴音乐]
Oh.
哦。
Mustard. Ahhh!
芥末。啊啊！
I struck mustard!
我打了芥末！
- Mustard?
- 芥末？
all: ♪ Look at all
the mustard flow ♪
全部：♪ 看看全部
芥末流♪
♪ Look at all
the mustard flow ♪
♪ 看看所有
芥末流♪
♪ That golden yellow
fatty acid treat ♪
♪ 那金黄色
脂肪酸治疗♪
[whirring]
[呼呼]
[thump]
[扑通]
- [spits]
- [吐口水]
[grunts]
[咕哝]
Oh, no,
what are we gonna do now?
哦，不，
我们现在要做什么？
- I think we better
use our heads.
- 我认为我们更好
用我们的头脑。
- Let's use my head.
- 让我们用我的头脑吧。
[grunting, whirring]
[咕噜声，呼呼声]
[slack-key guitar music]
[松键吉他音乐]
- Argh.
- 啊。
Argh.
啊。
all: The Mummy!
全体：妈咪！
- Stop!
- 停止！
[groaning]
[cork pops out]
[呻吟]
[软木塞弹出]
- [gasps]
It's the Mummy's Curse guy.
- [喘气]
这是木乃伊诅咒的家伙。
- There ain't no curse.
- 没有诅咒。
I just tried to discourage you
chuckleheads
我只是想劝阻你
傻瓜
from mining
this mustard.
来自采矿
这个芥末。
- Oh, I get it,
- 哦，我明白了，
'cause the mummy
wants the mustard.
因为木乃伊
想要芥末。
Mystery solved.
all: Hurrah!
谜团解开了。
全体：万岁！
- 'Tain't no Mummy.
- “没有妈妈。”
This mustard
is sitting on top of
这个芥末
坐在上面
20 million pounds
of pressure.
2000万英镑
的压力。
If you open her up,
she's gonna blow sky high.
如果你打开她的心扉
她会飞得很高。
- Oh, no curse.
- 哦，没有诅咒。
No mummy.
没有妈咪。
And no mustard.
而且没有芥末。
And I'll have
to find another job.
我会有
寻找另一份工作。
[weeps]
[哭泣]
[nose blows]
[擤鼻子]
- Stop.
Don't you see?
- 停止。
你没看到吗？
This old coot wants all
the mustard for himself.
这个老傻瓜想要一切
芥末给自己。
Now uncork that mustard.
现在打开芥末。
- Hmm?
[growls]
- 唔？
[咆哮]
- Oh, put your fists down,
old man.
- 哦，放下你的拳头，
老头儿。
I'm not gonna hurt you.
我不会伤害你。
- Hyah!
- 哈！
- You were right, Squidward,
you're not gonna hurt him.
- 你是对的，章鱼哥，
你不会伤害他的。
- Why you...
- 为什么你...
Ow.
噢。
[grunts]
I'm gonna--
[咕哝]
我要--
[groaning]
[呻吟]
- Go Squidward, you're winning.
You're not hurting him at all.
- 去章鱼哥吧，你赢了。
你根本没有伤害他。
- Let me try not hurting him.
- 让我尽量不伤害他。
- [speaking gibberish]
- [胡言乱语]
- Come on, old-timer.
- 来吧，老家伙。
You know you want
a piece of me.
你知道你想要
我的一部分。
- [growls]
- [咆哮]
- Oh.
- 哦。
- Ow, that hurt.
- 噢，好痛。
- I hurt him.
- 我伤害了他。
That means I lose.
这意味着我输了。
[mine rumbles]
[地雷的隆隆声]
- [whimpering]
- [呜咽]
- No, no, no, no, no, no, no.
- 不，不，不，不，不，不，不。
[suspenseful music]
[悬疑音乐]
Whoa...
哇...
- Adiós, muchachos.
- 再见，再见。
[laughing]
[笑]
[calm elevator music]
[平静的电梯音乐]
- [whimpering]
Hmm.
- [呜咽]
嗯。
[telephone rings]
[电话铃声]
I'll get it.
Hello.
我会得到它。
你好。
- Where's me mustard?
- 我在哪里芥末？
- Um...
- 嗯...
- No.
Ow.
- 不。
噢。
[angry chatter]
[愤怒的喋喋不休]
♪ ♪
- Your mustard
is coming right up.
- 你的芥末
马上就要来了。
- When?
- Now?
- 什么时候？
- 现在？
♪ ♪
- Wow!
Yee-ha!
- 哇！
呀哈！
Yeah.
是的。
[delighted chatter]
[高兴的喋喋不休]
[upbeat music]
[欢快的音乐]
- What, no relish?
- 什么，没胃口？